<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Society on Thoughts From a Dragonfly</title><link>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/tags/society/</link><description>Recent content in Society on Thoughts From a Dragonfly</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/tags/society/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Knowledge — A Societal Driving Force</title><link>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/cover.webp" alt="Featured image of post Knowledge — A Societal Driving Force" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/1.webp"
width="800"
height="1200"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/1_hu_275db9932473981a.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/1_hu_c8e13934d8594ec1.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="66"
data-flex-basis="160px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is a goal, a goal impossible to reach. A goal scholar pursues their entire existence, knowing its unfeasibility. It is the peak of the highest mountain that mountaineers, weak and strong alike, climb, knowing their grave lies amidst the snow. It is a thought that intoxicates all who see its value and allows them to persevere through the climb to conquer more of the mountain and accept their ascertained defeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/2.webp"
width="600"
height="600"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/2_hu_8fb26df86dcf5199.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/2_hu_771b578b6cfa3c2.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="100"
data-flex-basis="240px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is the pinnacle of thought and understanding of everything that is to be understood. Knowledge about the small atoms that work in unison to produce marvelous chemical machines, to the grand universe of unfathomable complexity. Knowledge about the predictable day after a long night to the stochasticity of the clouds encompassing our globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is a key. A key that unlocks opportunity itself. From a simple job interview to the cure for cancer, it holds the very secret to things humans value most. A small, golden key in a world made of locks. Knowledge is key to every job, family, conversation, culture, achievement, and goal humans can think of, yet it remains a goal impossible to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/3.webp"
width="284"
height="177"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/3_hu_b7489cb058819b28.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/3_hu_c257168983de8ef3.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="160"
data-flex-basis="385px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is a beacon that illuminates the path to all human desires. A beacon so bright as to irradiate outer space and the abyssal depths of the ocean. It is a tool that can show an enlightening path to peace and prosperity and the inhumane weapons of war. A beacon that — not only sheds light on the path ahead — but also illuminates the characteristics of the person holding the torch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although some might say that knowledge is attainable in a topic of smaller scope, to say that a subset of an infinite expanse of knowledge is finite would be to say that the human race has perfected certain fields, and nothing new can be obtained from them. A complete understanding of a certain field would require a complete understanding of knowledge itself since every component of this universe is linked — often in subtle ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is a question as old as time itself. It materializes in many forms, from the inherent order in nature to “Cogito, ergo sum.” It is an existential question, unanswerable by even the greatest intellect. It is a question that trumps all questions in comparison, whose answer unlocks the very mysteries of nature itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While some think they have attained knowledge, and many more believe it is attainable in a human lifespan, we must consider the minuscule role we play in the infinite expanse of our universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/4.webp"
width="352"
height="143"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/4_hu_335328f34dce5341.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/4_hu_dd54d69804692c58.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="246"
data-flex-basis="590px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Blight Upon Humanity: The Education System</title><link>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/blight-upon-humanity-the-education-system/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/blight-upon-humanity-the-education-system/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/blight-upon-humanity-the-education-system/cover.webp" alt="Featured image of post Blight Upon Humanity: The Education System" /&gt;&lt;h2 id="the-education-system"&gt;The Education System
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many believe that math is all about 1+2 and a+b and just a conglomeration of random facts and virtual things meant to waste students’ time. Furthermore, they question why study chemistry, physics, biology, etc. And every person in the modern education system will likely agree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact is that the modern education system is based on a few hundred-year-old, textbook-based lifestyle, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t adequately suit the mindset of the generation today. Many things aren’t told to “prevent confusion” or “make it easier” that certainly worked 200 years ago, but have an adverse effect today. Today, they make students study and memorize equations, memorize names, dates, and places. They “teach” students formulas that look foreign to students’ naive eyes. And even though there is a beautiful reason, proof, explanation, or logic behind every single one of these topics, it has been concealed in the interest of time and money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/blight-upon-humanity-the-education-system/1.webp"
width="1100"
height="878"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/blight-upon-humanity-the-education-system/1_hu_f4fe1976fe4473cd.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/blight-upon-humanity-the-education-system/1_hu_93ad88a83f0442d.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="125"
data-flex-basis="300px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Higher precedence is given to tests and quizzes than to the acquisition of knowledge and understanding. Although tests are important to assess the depth of a student’s knowledge of a topic, there is a lack of coordination among teachers. This tessellates testing schedules such that students have tests and quizzes almost every single day. What purpose do they serve in teaching the student the beauty of this planet? Isn’t the true purpose of education to demystify the intricate mysteries this world possesses? Or is it to assess students, rank them, and sort them into groups based on their ability to persevere and sustain the pain these tests impose?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/blight-upon-humanity-the-education-system/2.webp"
width="1100"
height="733"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/blight-upon-humanity-the-education-system/2_hu_9d7d5e17fd182838.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/blight-upon-humanity-the-education-system/2_hu_a91b0e86db55fa24.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="150"
data-flex-basis="360px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-promise"&gt;The Promise
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;What if there was a world where the education system was a flexible string, on which students can gain experience, learn, and appreciate the world? What if the system was dedicated to finding the true nature of every student? Every person has a skill that they excel at; and if this skill is found early, the student greatly benefits from the fruits a hobby has to offer. If not, the student is forced to pick a stream of their choice after 4 years of general studies like mathematics, reading, science, and history. Imagine if each student was passionate about a subject so much that they would spend all of their free time on it? This would, of course, be in addition to the traditional courses taught intuitively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that it is the education system’s job to assist students in discovering their passion for a field of study. This will exponentially increase the skill-set in the workforce and provide the world an avenue to rapidly expand and innovate. Instead of working in jobs, why can’t people make discoveries, find problems and solutions, and have an urge to help society? Isn’t that the true purpose of education? Isn’t that the purpose of humanity?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/blight-upon-humanity-the-education-system/3.webp"
width="1024"
height="512"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/blight-upon-humanity-the-education-system/3_hu_3a45eebd1750a136.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/blight-upon-humanity-the-education-system/3_hu_a90930a6d382f6ea.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="200"
data-flex-basis="480px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="real-education"&gt;Real Education
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, I am not saying that what students learn in the education system is incorrect. Quite the opposite actually. I think that the education system is teaching the correct subjects and topics, but simply in the wrong fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="mathematics-in-the-real-world"&gt;Mathematics in the real world
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am sure you remember learning about hyperbolic functions like &lt;code&gt;sinh&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;cosh&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;tanh&lt;/code&gt;. I am sure you found them completely unrelatable and useless. But look at the images below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/blight-upon-humanity-the-education-system/4.webp"
width="1100"
height="733"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/blight-upon-humanity-the-education-system/4_hu_b3cf807d7de6badc.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/blight-upon-humanity-the-education-system/4_hu_61e9be67b83ab062.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="150"
data-flex-basis="360px"
&gt;
&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/blight-upon-humanity-the-education-system/5.webp"
width="240"
height="300"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/blight-upon-humanity-the-education-system/5_hu_60fe80aed0e432c8.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/blight-upon-humanity-the-education-system/5_hu_e06b0489093e728e.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="80"
data-flex-basis="192px"
&gt;
&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/blight-upon-humanity-the-education-system/6.webp"
width="450"
height="300"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/blight-upon-humanity-the-education-system/6_hu_82d1b4bf70a6c1a8.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/blight-upon-humanity-the-education-system/6_hu_a981f92ebdfa64f0.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="150"
data-flex-basis="360px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you notice a similarity? Some engineers wanted to ensure that a hanging bridge is safe. So, they tried to model a bridge, hanging on ropes, using a curve. They could NOT find a single curve that fits the bridge. Only when they found hyperbolic functions were they able to perfectly model the bridge. In fact, any flexible material suspended in the air by 2 points follows this curve!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out that hyperbolic functions are everywhere in nature. Bubbles always try to reduce their surface area. They follow the catenary curve(&lt;code&gt;cosh(x)&lt;/code&gt;)! These curves are now used anywhere that requires string or optimized shapes. Any energy-optimization, area-optimization, etc. requires these functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="improvements"&gt;Improvements
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id="hobby-searching"&gt;Hobby Searching
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The schools should assist students to find their hobbies and teach them the general curriculum in a more intuitive way. This is the only way to cultivate a strong and specialized community that can advance our civilization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="curriculum"&gt;Curriculum
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;They should explain the proofs, logic, and implications of everything students learn. They should teach us the logic, not the rules. Students should learn the history of mathematics and science. Students should be taught the genesis of each formula, theorem, and concept. Only when students understand why they are learning these topics, will they truly understand the meaning behind them. After that, there will be no need for studying or preparation, everyone will intrinsically understand the lessons. They will see applications of it anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The modern education system consists of antique courses and teaching methods from the Industrial Revolution. This doesn’t benefit the more curious, modern generation. I would like you to contemplate today; when you were in the schooling system, were these your opinions too?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>