<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Philosophy on Thoughts From a Dragonfly</title><link>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/categories/philosophy/</link><description>Recent content in Philosophy on Thoughts From a Dragonfly</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/categories/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Knowledge — A Societal Driving Force</title><link>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/cover.webp" alt="Featured image of post Knowledge — A Societal Driving Force" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/1.webp"
width="800"
height="1200"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/1_hu_275db9932473981a.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/1_hu_c8e13934d8594ec1.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="66"
data-flex-basis="160px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is a goal, a goal impossible to reach. A goal scholar pursues their entire existence, knowing its unfeasibility. It is the peak of the highest mountain that mountaineers, weak and strong alike, climb, knowing their grave lies amidst the snow. It is a thought that intoxicates all who see its value and allows them to persevere through the climb to conquer more of the mountain and accept their ascertained defeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/2.webp"
width="600"
height="600"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/2_hu_8fb26df86dcf5199.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/2_hu_771b578b6cfa3c2.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="100"
data-flex-basis="240px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is the pinnacle of thought and understanding of everything that is to be understood. Knowledge about the small atoms that work in unison to produce marvelous chemical machines, to the grand universe of unfathomable complexity. Knowledge about the predictable day after a long night to the stochasticity of the clouds encompassing our globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is a key. A key that unlocks opportunity itself. From a simple job interview to the cure for cancer, it holds the very secret to things humans value most. A small, golden key in a world made of locks. Knowledge is key to every job, family, conversation, culture, achievement, and goal humans can think of, yet it remains a goal impossible to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/3.webp"
width="284"
height="177"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/3_hu_b7489cb058819b28.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/3_hu_c257168983de8ef3.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="160"
data-flex-basis="385px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is a beacon that illuminates the path to all human desires. A beacon so bright as to irradiate outer space and the abyssal depths of the ocean. It is a tool that can show an enlightening path to peace and prosperity and the inhumane weapons of war. A beacon that — not only sheds light on the path ahead — but also illuminates the characteristics of the person holding the torch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although some might say that knowledge is attainable in a topic of smaller scope, to say that a subset of an infinite expanse of knowledge is finite would be to say that the human race has perfected certain fields, and nothing new can be obtained from them. A complete understanding of a certain field would require a complete understanding of knowledge itself since every component of this universe is linked — often in subtle ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is a question as old as time itself. It materializes in many forms, from the inherent order in nature to “Cogito, ergo sum.” It is an existential question, unanswerable by even the greatest intellect. It is a question that trumps all questions in comparison, whose answer unlocks the very mysteries of nature itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While some think they have attained knowledge, and many more believe it is attainable in a human lifespan, we must consider the minuscule role we play in the infinite expanse of our universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/4.webp"
width="352"
height="143"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/4_hu_335328f34dce5341.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/4_hu_dd54d69804692c58.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="246"
data-flex-basis="590px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why Humanity is DOOMED!</title><link>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/cover.webp" alt="Featured image of post Why Humanity is DOOMED!" /&gt;&lt;h2 id="it-is-not-what-you-think"&gt;It is not what you think…
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We(specifically the &lt;em&gt;Homo&lt;/em&gt; genus) have been on this beautiful planet for over 7000 millennia or 7 million years. For 95% of that time, we have intensively depended on our environment and local resources to thrive. Progress was slow, but so was the damage. We made tools out of rocks and sticks. A few million years later, we found brass, copper, iron, tin, etc., and life for all species on Earth was irreversibly altered. The avalanche was triggered on Everest, and even the most experienced mountain climbers can’t control it. Typically, these climbers would retreat to their base and allow the avalanche to pass, but their sheer confidence in their ability and self-proclaimed prowess in the mountains tells them to ignore the avalanche and reach the summit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/1.webp"
width="436"
height="280"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/1_hu_590e34c64a1afb40.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/1_hu_692f065f4adb2fca.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="155"
data-flex-basis="373px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-have-we-done"&gt;What have we done?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It took decades to foresee but visionaries, like Stephen Hawking, understood the ignored consequences of our careless actions. Most people only see the first 2 feet of the mile-deep hole we drilled. Contrary to popular opinion, it isn’t simply about resource depletion or environmental damage. While those are significant components, it isn’t the complete story. In fact, the most important factor has been erased from your brain by contemporary politics! The human mentality has collectively deteriorated beyond repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/2.webp"
width="1100"
height="825"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/2_hu_f50f85a22f277466.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/2_hu_8a47af263e81ed34.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please note&lt;/strong&gt;: This next section is not a critique of particular countries. Applying these accusations to a particular state or nation is your opinion and not our words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="reveal-the-truth"&gt;Reveal the truth…
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Capitalism, greed, money, and power have become the primary purpose of human existence. Doctors take their oath to help people, only to purposefully reject some people of their service for money. Politicians make extravagant claims, only to sit on power and money once their position is confirmed. People bear arms and kill innocent civilians inexplicably. Businesses never think twice when selling private user information, violating their privacy policy, to earn money. In the history of our world, knowledge has never had a price. Today, it costs more money than a house to acquire an education worthy of any value in this judgmental world. While a nation’s sole responsibility is to protect its citizens, today, they are enchanted by powerful weapons and make people pay huge sums of taxes and bills for life necessities like insurance and education. Nations who fought to eliminate taxes from their imperialistic parent country, are now imposing massive taxes and ignoring the financially impaired!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/3.webp"
width="600"
height="442"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/3_hu_67dbfa309db8a315.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/3_hu_2e07bbfe6f0d2518.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="135"
data-flex-basis="325px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We like to think that we are smart, but our actions prove otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-can-you-do"&gt;What can you do?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While these accusations were directed at countries and “more influential people”. This is, in fact, another pitfall of human mentality. Every person can make a difference, however, we choose not to. Speaking out about selfish actions, displaying kind human nature, and aiming to leave the world slightly better than you first saw it is the best thing you can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/4.webp"
width="757"
height="439"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/4_hu_df9c87bd562a3928.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/4_hu_84236e756d12f41d.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="172"
data-flex-basis="413px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why-does-it-matter--butterfly-effect"&gt;Why does it matter? — Butterfly Effect
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The butterfly effect is a branch of chaos theory aiming to show how an infinitesimal change in a deterministic state can result in drastic consequences in the future. Smiling and greeting a neighbor can prevent a murder! Publishing an article about the world can inspire others to rise and save our unrivaled blue planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/5.webp"
width="1100"
height="610"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/5_hu_9bb490e0ccfe7337.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/5_hu_2afe98d5946ef388.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="180"
data-flex-basis="432px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Will Automation Take Your Job?</title><link>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/will-automation-take-your-job/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/will-automation-take-your-job/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/will-automation-take-your-job/cover.webp" alt="Featured image of post Will Automation Take Your Job?" /&gt;&lt;h2 id="what-is-robotics"&gt;What is Robotics?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Robotics, put simply, is the combination of electrical, software, and mechanical engineering to make tasks easier. But, the amount of robots being used in repetitive tasks in warehouses and factories is exponentially growing. This begs the question, will the rapid popularization of automation diminish the need for humans?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why-do-people-do-these-jobs"&gt;Why do People do These Jobs?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oftentimes, people are compelled to do these jobs due to their unfortunate economic conditions. Debt from school, high unemployment due to a desperate global economy, and low levels of education can all put people in these types of jobs. People need the money to survive and a spiraling concern is their ensuing replacement by machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/will-automation-take-your-job/1.webp"
width="650"
height="488"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/will-automation-take-your-job/1_hu_63fbab508db60017.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/will-automation-take-your-job/1_hu_3793ebcaf8702dfa.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="319px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-can-robots-currently-do"&gt;What Can Robots Currently Do?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the general public only knows a fraction of the true potential of robotics. Some AIs create perfectly synthetic art from a single sentence description. Others make hyper-realistic human faces and write code for you just from a description! Some robots mow your lawn, weld entire car frames together, and even make Falcon 9 rockets that go to space. AIs have been used to design and manufacture the very airplanes you fly in. The advertisements we see are custom generated for each user using cookies and digital biometrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/will-automation-take-your-job/2.webp"
width="1100"
height="733"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/will-automation-take-your-job/2_hu_4bad117cbd7453b7.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/will-automation-take-your-job/2_hu_e67b3e27d72e0d40.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="150"
data-flex-basis="360px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-light-at-the-end-of-the-tunnel"&gt;The Light at the End of the Tunnel!
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the insane advancements in robotics, a technological revolution akin to this one has happened before. The industrial revolution, in particular, the advent of the steam engine sharply reduced the need for physical labor. The cotton gin and the mechanized loom left hundreds of thousands unemployed, and because of this people found new jobs to maintain the machines. In fact, this drastically increased the mean education level of people around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/will-automation-take-your-job/3.webp"
width="620"
height="330"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/will-automation-take-your-job/3_hu_af5e27374a5dea6c.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/will-automation-take-your-job/3_hu_a2dc551ab8edede1.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="187"
data-flex-basis="450px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-future-outlook"&gt;The Future Outlook
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the ominous clouds that hover over the future of AI and jobs, the grim attitude towards robotics research may be unnecessary. The next 50 years will be economically uninviting, the future of robotics will promote higher education, and innovation, and provide people with jobs that require human intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Truth About Humans</title><link>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/1.webp" alt="Featured image of post The Truth About Humans" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is fair to say that humans are a dominating species on our blue planet. And certainly, the question must have crossed your mind at some point, “Why humans?” In retrospect, we make a mess wherever we go. The Great Garbage Patch, global warming, mass hunting and extinction, habitat loss, and there are several more. But that is not all! We savagely kill each other and fight for the most insignificant things. We are selfish, greedy, and vengeful. In fact, we eradicated several other species of humans like the Neanderthals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="intelligence"&gt;Intelligence
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/1.webp"
width="882"
height="588"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/1_hu_1d4826cbf96eb079.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/1_hu_4df3c7b6acc9d295.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="150"
data-flex-basis="360px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The standard argument that everyone convinces themselves with is, “We are smarter.” There are several flaws with this. What is smartness? If it is defined by multidimensional thinking, many animals like whales and dolphins beat us. This is because they have larger brains with more gyri(folds in the brain) that increase spatial thinking abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it memory? Nope. Chimpanzees have a significantly better memory than us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/2.webp"
width="320"
height="244"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/2_hu_d14dddccf64f6590.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/2_hu_ebcf61517c51e19e.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="131"
data-flex-basis="314px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it language? Evidently not. Parrots can comprehend and retain languages extremely quickly. And wolves communicate and coordinate attacks in seamless precision. It can be compared to a special ops military attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/3.webp"
width="1100"
height="880"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/3_hu_4723f35d0bc2096e.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/3_hu_c52e8e6fc8c70289.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="125"
data-flex-basis="300px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A critic might propose that we are simply the culmination of all these animals and that is why we dominate. However, the octopus contains all the traits mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="octopii"&gt;Octopii
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Octopuses have the perfect proportion of memory, recognition, spatial thinking, pattern recognizing, agility, strength, etc. While we have roughly 60 protocadherins, octopuses have approximately 168! This means that they have 3 times the neural wiring capacity as us humans. Then why don’t we see octopuses making mansions and instruments and conducting mathematics?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/4.webp"
width="821"
height="600"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/4_hu_a0685d0baad8e23f.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/4_hu_a09b1499ef99c44.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="136"
data-flex-basis="328px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-hard-truth"&gt;The Hard Truth
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We humans have no idea. If octopuses desired, they could certainly advance to our level and challenge the human species. They have already done numerous feats like solving Rubik&amp;rsquo;s cubes, solving other puzzles, and using mechanical advantage in their tools. They have all the resources we have on land, including minerals, chemicals, precious metals, and plastic bags(thanks to us). Then why do we see octopuses still using snail shells to protect themselves? Why haven’t octopuses created utopias and colonies underwater? Why can’t they make themselves a palace of coral and live in peace?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/5.webp"
width="302"
height="167"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/5_hu_f6b1588de6831103.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/5_hu_a4621fd94054a592.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="180"
data-flex-basis="434px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-difference"&gt;The Difference
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As enunciated previously, we are greedy. We don’t care about sustainability or the environment we depend on. We care about self-preservation and comfort. Maybe, the octopuses have realized the importance of nature. Octopuses have existed on Earth for 500 MILLION years as opposed to us, amateurs, who have existed for a mere 6 million years. Conceivably from their previous experience, they have understood the harsh lessons we are only now realizing. Perhaps they changed their lifestyle before it was too late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/6.webp"
width="800"
height="533"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/6_hu_aa0c13eb45b37454.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/6_hu_b31cc8cb3e8d62ed.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="150"
data-flex-basis="360px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-key-takeaway"&gt;The Key Takeaway
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We NEED to learn from the octopuses. We MUST let go of our ego and learn from these wise and experience creatures that have been on this planet for magnitudes more than us. And it is not just the octopuses, but every animal on Earth. Humans are unarguably the most unsustainable species on Earth contrasting with almost all other animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many animals that can challenge the human race if they wished. But, they have more sustainable practices and goals than us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If octopuses went through the scientific, technological, and economic advancements that we are going through, it would be impossible to prove millions of years later. The dynamic ocean would have concealed the slightest traces of technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, while we think that octopuses, chimpanzees, goats, etc. are just animals, there is a motive to consider why that is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/7.webp"
width="1637"
height="1831"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/7_hu_1c3330eeef600632.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/the-truth-about-humans/7_hu_21c99d2f69d6c222.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="89"
data-flex-basis="214px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AI Ethics — Crucial Law or Theoretical Philosophy</title><link>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-ethics-philosophy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-ethics-philosophy/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-ethics-philosophy/cover.webp" alt="Featured image of post AI Ethics — Crucial Law or Theoretical Philosophy" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have all heard of or even discussed ethics before. Some may have even heard of a new field of philosophy called “AI Ethics.” But what is it really?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ai-ethics"&gt;AI Ethics
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This emerging field of philosophy deals with the primary question &lt;em&gt;“If a person made a sentient machine or program, would shutting the program down or turning off the computer be equivalent to killing it?”&lt;/em&gt; Your immediate answer may be &lt;em&gt;“No, it is just a computer that WE made!”&lt;/em&gt; But let me provide you with a series of questions that provide depth to this problem!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="iq"&gt;IQ
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;IQ is a general measure of multi-spatial thinking. If a robot has the IQ of a dog or cat, can’t we equate it to a dog or cat? But others might say that AI is not really thinking and is simply predicting from a defined set of data. But how do we know what humans or other animals are thinking? Just because we have a larger dataset and more processing power doesn’t mean we are thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="material-crisis"&gt;Material Crisis
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another justification to &lt;em&gt;“pull the plug”&lt;/em&gt; might be to say that the AI is simply a bunch of transistors, plastic, and metal. But how can we consider humans superior to robots? After all, we are made of oxygen, hydrogen, nitrogen, and other elements. Our brain is simply a bunch of electrical signals(sounds familiar?), and our emotions are just specific chemical compounds released during specific events. Computers(frankly technology in general) are just a simple reflection of us and the way we think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-ethics-philosophy/1.webp"
width="612"
height="612"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-ethics-philosophy/1_hu_8cd23360a88a285f.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-ethics-philosophy/1_hu_f18d47618d93d675.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="100"
data-flex-basis="240px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ship-of-theseus-problem"&gt;Ship of Theseus Problem
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine you have a boat that is sailing a hundred miles. But, you couldn’t shell out enough shillings for a fancy-pants boat so you went to the dark alley at midnight and bought one from a guy in a hood. So along the way, your boat fell apart piece by piece and you summoned replacement parts to fix it. When it reached its destination, you ended up replacing EVERY single part of it. Is this still the same boat? If so, what if a storm destroyed the entire boat and you built it from scratch so it is identical to the original? Is it still the same boat then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scenario here is asking if it is the parts that define an object or the experience the boat went through. This matters because depending on the interpretation you take you could argue that if you turn off the AI, but turn on the exact same version later, you didn’t kill the ai. Now, you may have a completely different opinion about the Material Crisis. Now, it doesn’t matter if you are made of steel or cells, what matters is the experiences you make with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-ethics-philosophy/2.webp"
width="1100"
height="733"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-ethics-philosophy/2_hu_adfe6a08d21a4da6.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-ethics-philosophy/2_hu_9cd3e4ff6f72747e.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="150"
data-flex-basis="360px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="so-what"&gt;So What?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;What sets us(humans made of cells, flesh, and bone) from them(robots made of steel, motors, and a frame)? If there is no major difference setting us apart, then why would killing a sentient robot be justified? And if a robot has consciousness, should we consider it equal to us? After all, humans consider themselves superior to animals in many ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="so-is-there-just-1-answer"&gt;So is there just 1 answer?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;No, not really. What if an AI has the potential to be sentient but is still growing? Can we kill that? Just because it isn’t currently sentient doesn’t mean anything. Humans come from a single cell that is not technically sentient. But as the baby develops, it grows the ability to have sentience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 3 frames of view:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No life matters and killing anything(human, animal, or robot) is okay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some life matters(ethnocentric; humans matter but not animals and robots)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All life matters and killing is NOT justified.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="potential-ideas"&gt;Potential Ideas
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id="battery"&gt;Battery
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What if we make a sentient AI and then let it run on battery power until it drains and dies. Technically, it lived its maximum lifespan and its “heart stopped beating”. But you, the inventor, had the ability to swap or attach another battery or an external power source. That is equivalent to a doctor giving a heart transplant. Would a doctor deny your transplant, would you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-ethics-philosophy/3.webp"
width="553"
height="311"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-ethics-philosophy/3_hu_ac8fcb6f7a870185.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-ethics-philosophy/3_hu_a8ac5108ed684d71.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="426px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="teach-self-termination-sequence"&gt;Teach Self-Termination Sequence
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What if the first thing you taught the AI is to terminate and wipe the OS on user command? That would be the equivalent of a human “committing suicide”. But, didn’t you “pressure” the robot to do it? Just because a hitman kills a person doesn’t mean that the employer(of the hitman) isn’t at fault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-ethics-philosophy/4.webp"
width="350"
height="233"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-ethics-philosophy/4_hu_35fa207c274d3991.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-ethics-philosophy/4_hu_f85049b11e4a5768.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="150"
data-flex-basis="360px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="soul"&gt;Soul
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many may argue that a soul sets biological beings apart from robots. But, what is a soul? Who made it? Is it a subconscious state of the brain or a separate entity running our body? Or is a soul just something made up by humans to try to set them apart from everything else?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-ethics-philosophy/5.webp"
width="1600"
height="640"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-ethics-philosophy/5_hu_4dfd9450c4e40129.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-ethics-philosophy/5_hu_bfb599aa0452fd2b.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="250"
data-flex-basis="600px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oftentimes, this decision involves religion and personal biases. But, it is crucial to think about these topics as General Intelligence may not be as far as we think, or hope!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AI - A Problem or Our Salvation</title><link>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-problem-salvation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-problem-salvation/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-problem-salvation/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post AI - A Problem or Our Salvation" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to AI or robotics, the common public reaction is perceivable. When they talk about global domination by robots or job loss due to advances in robotics, their assumptions are highly based on science fiction and not that much on reality. In fact, robotics is an indistinguishable part of our lives and essential to us in a controlled manner. Whether you are strongly against anything related to robotics or are a lead engineer at &lt;a class="link" href="https://bostondynamics.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Boston Dynamics&lt;/a&gt;, it is indisputable that robotics is in our everyday lives.
&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-problem-salvation/1.webp"
width="1000"
height="769"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-problem-salvation/1_hu_afa071431f89701a.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-problem-salvation/1_hu_c8a9a3b1a7475bb7.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Image 1"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="130"
data-flex-basis="312px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything from a toaster, to your computer, there is some form of robotics in it. For example, while you are browsing on Amazon and it suggests you exactly what you are looking for, you witnessed AI. AI has just helped you and Amazon. After introducing this AI, Amazon saw a 29% increase in sales and $12.83 billion more dollars in revenue. This shows that AI is helping customers like you and companies like Amazon earn money. In fact, our lives are also at the hands of AI. Boeing and other companies are creating more efficient airplane air-frames using AI. They have trained the AI to take their requirements and it will design the most perfect air-frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-problem-salvation/2.webp"
width="852"
height="480"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-problem-salvation/2_hu_4c3f30e2f06485c6.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-problem-salvation/2_hu_d89679f3cca419ee.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Image by @boscorelli on Shutterstock"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="426px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Boeing, their new Boeing 777 will be 100% computer generated and assembled online before they even bring out the materials! In fact, the computer will even create a special mixture of metals and composites to make the air-frame lighter! Look around, every item near you is probably manufactured in a factory. In the year 2020 alone, 1.64 million industrial robots are used in factories around the globe and analytics say that they will replace 20 million factory jobs by 2030! This raises the concern that our interdependence might lead to severe problems depicted by literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ethical aspect of AI has been an extremely controversial topic. There is great hope that AI can personalize school learning plans, help disabled people, and revolutionize our lives, but there must be a balance. At a deeper level, AI is just a math equation that runs behind it but its ability to gradually learn is one fact that concerns many.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-problem-salvation/3.webp"
width="546"
height="223"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-problem-salvation/3_hu_ba4e6a8c11446862.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-problem-salvation/3_hu_bc81f184174d4ad6.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="The basic formula for AI."
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="244"
data-flex-basis="587px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though, if AI can be used conservatively and concisely, the severity of the consequence may be minimal. That raises a question though; as human beings, we are very curious, and we will strive to learn more and eventually lead to problems much greater than our imagination. But how severe is severe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-problem-salvation/4.webp"
width="500"
height="281"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-problem-salvation/4_hu_fa033ece9db8f40.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-problem-salvation/4_hu_42522172c046466.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Bryan Ward | Flickr"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="427px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That rhetorical question has quite a simple answer. AI is being developed in individual parts like some work on vision while others work on speech. Other engineers work on the robotic humanoid part. When a person gets the idea of combining all the parts, he/she will make a close replica of a human, and if not given the right knowledge of ethics and society, the robot will believe that it is one of us. As humans are quite violent, in the sense that we are always fighting each other, the robots will do the same. Many people discriminate, the robots will do the same. They will be our replica only made of metal and 100 times stronger. This is what we fear and if not controlled, we won’t have to watch movies to fear it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-problem-salvation/5.webp"
width="720"
height="480"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-problem-salvation/5_hu_f3650369974754d4.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/ai-problem-salvation/5_hu_20235fd6d51cd81.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Image 5"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="150"
data-flex-basis="360px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To conclude, the question is not whether AI is ethical but rather where is the limit. We must learn to live within boundaries and know that exceeding them can have grave consequences. The research our scientists have done is truly incredible but only to a limit. The next time you pull out a mobile phone or any other device, remember our interdependence with it and its similarity to any other robot or AI.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>