<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Future on Thoughts From a Dragonfly</title><link>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/tags/future/</link><description>Recent content in Future on Thoughts From a Dragonfly</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/tags/future/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Knowledge — A Societal Driving Force</title><link>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/cover.webp" alt="Featured image of post Knowledge — A Societal Driving Force" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/1.webp"
width="800"
height="1200"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/1_hu_275db9932473981a.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/1_hu_c8e13934d8594ec1.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="66"
data-flex-basis="160px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is a goal, a goal impossible to reach. A goal scholar pursues their entire existence, knowing its unfeasibility. It is the peak of the highest mountain that mountaineers, weak and strong alike, climb, knowing their grave lies amidst the snow. It is a thought that intoxicates all who see its value and allows them to persevere through the climb to conquer more of the mountain and accept their ascertained defeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/2.webp"
width="600"
height="600"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/2_hu_8fb26df86dcf5199.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/2_hu_771b578b6cfa3c2.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="100"
data-flex-basis="240px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is the pinnacle of thought and understanding of everything that is to be understood. Knowledge about the small atoms that work in unison to produce marvelous chemical machines, to the grand universe of unfathomable complexity. Knowledge about the predictable day after a long night to the stochasticity of the clouds encompassing our globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is a key. A key that unlocks opportunity itself. From a simple job interview to the cure for cancer, it holds the very secret to things humans value most. A small, golden key in a world made of locks. Knowledge is key to every job, family, conversation, culture, achievement, and goal humans can think of, yet it remains a goal impossible to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/3.webp"
width="284"
height="177"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/3_hu_b7489cb058819b28.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/3_hu_c257168983de8ef3.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="160"
data-flex-basis="385px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is a beacon that illuminates the path to all human desires. A beacon so bright as to irradiate outer space and the abyssal depths of the ocean. It is a tool that can show an enlightening path to peace and prosperity and the inhumane weapons of war. A beacon that — not only sheds light on the path ahead — but also illuminates the characteristics of the person holding the torch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although some might say that knowledge is attainable in a topic of smaller scope, to say that a subset of an infinite expanse of knowledge is finite would be to say that the human race has perfected certain fields, and nothing new can be obtained from them. A complete understanding of a certain field would require a complete understanding of knowledge itself since every component of this universe is linked — often in subtle ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is a question as old as time itself. It materializes in many forms, from the inherent order in nature to “Cogito, ergo sum.” It is an existential question, unanswerable by even the greatest intellect. It is a question that trumps all questions in comparison, whose answer unlocks the very mysteries of nature itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While some think they have attained knowledge, and many more believe it is attainable in a human lifespan, we must consider the minuscule role we play in the infinite expanse of our universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/4.webp"
width="352"
height="143"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/4_hu_335328f34dce5341.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/knowledge-a-societal-driving-force/4_hu_dd54d69804692c58.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="246"
data-flex-basis="590px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why Humanity is DOOMED!</title><link>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/cover.webp" alt="Featured image of post Why Humanity is DOOMED!" /&gt;&lt;h2 id="it-is-not-what-you-think"&gt;It is not what you think…
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We(specifically the &lt;em&gt;Homo&lt;/em&gt; genus) have been on this beautiful planet for over 7000 millennia or 7 million years. For 95% of that time, we have intensively depended on our environment and local resources to thrive. Progress was slow, but so was the damage. We made tools out of rocks and sticks. A few million years later, we found brass, copper, iron, tin, etc., and life for all species on Earth was irreversibly altered. The avalanche was triggered on Everest, and even the most experienced mountain climbers can’t control it. Typically, these climbers would retreat to their base and allow the avalanche to pass, but their sheer confidence in their ability and self-proclaimed prowess in the mountains tells them to ignore the avalanche and reach the summit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/1.webp"
width="436"
height="280"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/1_hu_590e34c64a1afb40.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/1_hu_692f065f4adb2fca.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="155"
data-flex-basis="373px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-have-we-done"&gt;What have we done?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It took decades to foresee but visionaries, like Stephen Hawking, understood the ignored consequences of our careless actions. Most people only see the first 2 feet of the mile-deep hole we drilled. Contrary to popular opinion, it isn’t simply about resource depletion or environmental damage. While those are significant components, it isn’t the complete story. In fact, the most important factor has been erased from your brain by contemporary politics! The human mentality has collectively deteriorated beyond repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/2.webp"
width="1100"
height="825"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/2_hu_f50f85a22f277466.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/2_hu_8a47af263e81ed34.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please note&lt;/strong&gt;: This next section is not a critique of particular countries. Applying these accusations to a particular state or nation is your opinion and not our words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="reveal-the-truth"&gt;Reveal the truth…
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Capitalism, greed, money, and power have become the primary purpose of human existence. Doctors take their oath to help people, only to purposefully reject some people of their service for money. Politicians make extravagant claims, only to sit on power and money once their position is confirmed. People bear arms and kill innocent civilians inexplicably. Businesses never think twice when selling private user information, violating their privacy policy, to earn money. In the history of our world, knowledge has never had a price. Today, it costs more money than a house to acquire an education worthy of any value in this judgmental world. While a nation’s sole responsibility is to protect its citizens, today, they are enchanted by powerful weapons and make people pay huge sums of taxes and bills for life necessities like insurance and education. Nations who fought to eliminate taxes from their imperialistic parent country, are now imposing massive taxes and ignoring the financially impaired!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/3.webp"
width="600"
height="442"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/3_hu_67dbfa309db8a315.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/3_hu_2e07bbfe6f0d2518.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="135"
data-flex-basis="325px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We like to think that we are smart, but our actions prove otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-can-you-do"&gt;What can you do?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While these accusations were directed at countries and “more influential people”. This is, in fact, another pitfall of human mentality. Every person can make a difference, however, we choose not to. Speaking out about selfish actions, displaying kind human nature, and aiming to leave the world slightly better than you first saw it is the best thing you can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/4.webp"
width="757"
height="439"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/4_hu_df9c87bd562a3928.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/4_hu_84236e756d12f41d.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="172"
data-flex-basis="413px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why-does-it-matter--butterfly-effect"&gt;Why does it matter? — Butterfly Effect
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The butterfly effect is a branch of chaos theory aiming to show how an infinitesimal change in a deterministic state can result in drastic consequences in the future. Smiling and greeting a neighbor can prevent a murder! Publishing an article about the world can inspire others to rise and save our unrivaled blue planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/5.webp"
width="1100"
height="610"
srcset="https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/5_hu_9bb490e0ccfe7337.webp 480w, https://thought.krishnashah.dev/p/why-humanity-is-doomed/5_hu_2afe98d5946ef388.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="180"
data-flex-basis="432px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>